Let's talk a bit more about why uncertainty is so
لنتحدث أكثر عن سبب أهمية الشك
important in the field of robotics and self-driving cars.
في مجال الروبوتات والسيارات ذاتية القيادة.
We know that measurements like the speed, the direction,
نحن نعلم أن قياس القياسات مثل سرعة سيارة
and the location of a car are challenging to measure and we can't measure them perfectly.
واتجاهها ومكانها أمرًا صعبًا للغاية بل يتعذر علينا قياسها تمامًا.
There's some uncertainty in each of these measurements.
يوجد بعض الشك في كل من هذه القياسات.
We also know that many of these measurements affect one another.
نحن نعلم أيضًا أن العديد من هذه القياسات تؤثر في بعضها البعض.
For example, if we are uncertain about the location of a car,
على سبيل المثال، إذا كنا غير متأكدين من مكان سيارة،
we can reduce that uncertainty by collecting data
يمكننا تقليل هذا الشك من خلال جمع البيانات
about the car's surroundings and its movement.
حول الأشياء المحيطة بالسيارة وحركتها.
Self-driving cars measure all of these things from a car's speed,
تقيس السيارات ذاتية القيادة جميع هذه الأشياء بدءًا من سرعة السيارة،
to the scenery and objects that surround it, with sensors.
وصوولًا للمشهد والأشياء التي تحيط بها باستخدام أجهزة الاستشعار.
And though these sensor measurements aren't perfect,
وعلى الرغم من أن قياسات المستشعر ليست مثالية،
when the information they provide is combined
عند جمع المعلومات التي تقدمها
using conditional probability and something called Bayes rule,
باستخدام الاحتمال الشرط وشيء يُسمى قاعدة Bayes،
they can form a reliable representation of a car's position,
يمكنها تشكيل تمثيلًا موثوقًا لوضع السيارة
its movement and its environment.
وحركتها وبيئتها.
Let's take a look at Bayes Rule.
لنلقِ نظرة على قاعدة Bayes.